A Finding Aid to the Fritz Bultman Papers, 1928-2010, bulk 1940s-1990s, in the Archives of American Art AAA.bultfrit
Archives of American Art
- Subject Files, 1942-2010; Series 7; 2.3 Linear feet Boxes 3-5, 11
  - College Art Association and Women's Caucus for Art (1982 February) -- Panel, "Artists Working in Collaboration" (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - "Cooking Letters", 1977 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Cornell, Joseph, undated (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - De Kooning, Willem, 1978-1990 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Tibor De Nagy Gallery, 1963-1970 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Dicky, Tina, 1992-1999 (Box 4, Folder 11-12)
  - Firestone, Evan R., 1993-2006 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - "Forum '49" and "Forum '49 Revisited", 1949-1999 (Box 4, Folder 14-15)
  - Muriel Bultman Francis Collection, undated; 1956-1986 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Fulbright Grant, 1963-1976 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Joseph C. Hawthorne 1986 Trust/Babcock Galleries, undated; 1983-2003 (Box 4, Folder 18-19)
  - Hofmann, Hans - Authentication of Hofmann Artwork, undated (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Hofmann, Hans -- Color Chart, undated (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Hofmann, Hans -- Printed Material, undated; 1941-1999 (Box 4, Folder 22-23)
  - Hofmann, Hans -- Writings by Hofmann, undated; 1932-1978 (Box 4, Folder 24-30)
  - House of Bultman, undated; 1964-1979 (Box 4, Folder 31)
    Additional informtion about the family business is filed with The Bultman Mortuary Service, Inc.
  - Independent Curators Incorporated, 1985-1990 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - James, Charles, 1963-1967; undated (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Kalamazoo College, 1980-2001 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Kees, Weldon, undated; 1979-1999 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Maxfield's Front Room, 1955 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Modern Art Foundry, Inc. plus Hellgate Hill, 1962-1973 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Mouton, Grover, circa 1978-circa 1985 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - New Orleans Museum of Art, "Fritz Bultman: A Retrospective", 1974-1993 (Box 5, Folder 6-8)
  - Paintings from Paris (Galerie Stadler), 2003-2004 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Paragraphs by Michael Stephens with Drawings by Fritz Bultman, 1974 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Price Lists, 1959-1991; undated (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Provincetown History Preservation Project, 2010 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Provincetown History Preservation Project, Inventory I (Bul 000-044), undated (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Provincetown History Preservation Project, Inventory I (Bul 000-047), 1960-1989 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Provincetown History Preservation Project, Inventory I, 1942-1952 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Provincetown History Preservation Project, Inventory I, 1942-1949 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Provincetown History Preservation Project, Inventory II, 1950-2008; undated (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Reynolds Aluminum, 1977-1979; undated (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Rothko, Mark, 1973-1978; undated (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - The Judith Rothschild Foundation, 1995-2001 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - "Small Sculptures," Bowling Green, Ohio, 1981 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Smith, Tony, 1938-1955 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - "Myron Stout: Selections for the Original Journals," edited by Chris Busa, 1997-1998 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Tougaloo College Art Collection, 1980; 1968 (Box 5, Folder 24-25)
  - The Turning Point: The Abstract Expressionists and the Transformation of American Art by April Kingsley -- Reviews, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Windham, Donald, undated, 1945-1986 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Oversized, 96th Street Playground Association Project, from Box 3, Folder 21, 1980 (Box 11)
- Printed Material, 1941-2006; Series 8; 3.5 Linear feet Boxes 5-9, OV 12
  Most items are about or mention Bultman. Exhibition catalogs, announcements, and reviews document his solo exhibitions and group shows. There are general and scholarly articles about him, along with publications containing reproductions of his work. Also found are a few articles by Bultman and catalogs of schools where he taught.
  This series is arranged chronologically. Additional printed material is scattered throughout the subject files (Series 7).
  - Printed Material, undated; 1941-1946; Oversized material housed in OV 12 (Box 5, Folder 28-30)
  - Printed Material, 1947-1969; Oversized material housed in OV 12 (Box 6, Folder 1-27)
  - Printed Material, 1970-1981; Oversized material housed in OV 12 (Box 7, Folder 1-21)
  - Printed Material, 1982-1998; Oversized material housed in OV 12 (Box 8, Folder 1-23)
  - Printed Material, 1999-2006 (Box 9, Folder 1-6)
  - Oversized Printed Material from Box 6, Folders 20-21, Box 7, folders 14-16, Box 8, Folder 1, 1982; 1963; 1978 (Box OV 12)
- Artwork, circa 1930s-1956; Series 9; 0.1 Linear feet Boxes 9, 11
  All artwork is by Bultman. Drawings, sketches and paintings are in pencil, ink, gouache and tempera on paper. This series also contains one print.
  Additional artwork is found in notebooks/sketchbooks (Series 5).
  - Drawings, Sketches, and Painting, 1956; undated; Oversized material housed in Box 11 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Print, undated (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Oversized Drawings from Box 9, folder 7, circa 1930s-1956 (Box 11)
- Photographs, 1935-1997; Series 10; 0.6 Linear feet Boxes 9-10
  Photographs are of artwork, exhibition installations, people, and places. This series also includes some negatives, color transparencies, and 35-mm color slides.
  Photographs of Bultman's artwork document his paintings, sculpture, and drawings, as well as his lesser known work in collage, stained glass, interior design and decoration. A view of destroyed interior murals he painted in the family home is included. In addition, there are a few photographs of artwork by Arthur B. Carles, Jean Dubuffet, John Graham, Ray Keyton, Myron Stout, and Jack Tworkov in a variety of media. Exhibition installation views are mainly of solo and retrospective shows in the United States, and two early exhibitions in Paris and Italy.
  Most photographs of people are Fritz Bultman, his family and friends. Many pictures of Bultman from the 1970s-1980s are by Renate Ponsold. Identified family and friends include: parents Fred and Pauline Bultman, sister Muriel Bultman, childhood nurse Katie Belle, son Ellis Johann Bultman, Sherman Drexler, Hans Hofmann, Miz Hofmann, Miss Katsura, Lee Krasner, Annalee Newman, Barnett Newman, Alfonso Ossorio, Jeanne Reynal, Thomas Sills, Jack Tworkov, and Wally Tworkov. There is also a group portrait of the artists of Long Point Gallery: Varujan Boghosian, Fritz Bultman, Carmen Cicero, Sideo Fromboluti, Budd Hopkins, Rick Klauber, Lee Manso, Sidney Simon, Robert Motherwell, Judith Rothschild, Nora Speyer, and Tony Vevers.
  Exhibition installation views are filed by date of exhibition; all other portions of this series are alphabetized by folder title. Photographs are also found among the subject files (Series 7).
  - Artwork by Bultman -- Collages (executed 1962-1983), circa 1980s (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Artwork by Bultman -- Collages and Mixed Media (executed 1938-1964), undated (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Artwork by Bultman -- Drawings (executed circa 1940s-1982), undated (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Artwork by Bultman - Drawings (executed 1985 May-July) (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Artwork by Bultman -- Interior Design and Decoration (executed circa 1940s), undated (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Artwork by Bultman -- Paintings (executed 1939-1959), undated (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Artwork by Bultman -- Paintings (executed 1941-1981), undated (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Artwork by Bultman -- Paintings (executed 1945-1983), undated (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Artwork by Bultman -- Paintings (executed 1947), undated (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Artwork by Bultman -- Sculpture (executed 1958-1977), undated (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Artwork by Bultman -- Sculpture and Collages (executed 1967-1978), undated (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Artwork by Bultman -- Sculpture and Painting, Paris Studio, 55 Boulevard Stelmans, 1964-1965 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Artwork by Bultman -- Stained Glass, circa 1967 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Artwork by Bultman -- Unidentified Collection, undated (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Artwork by Other Artists, undated (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Exhibition Installations -- Isaac Delgado Museum of Art; Galerie Stadler, Paris, 1959 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Exhibition Installations -- "Structure of the Sea," Gallerie Civica D'Arte Moderne, Torino, Italy, 1962 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Exhibition Installations -- Art Festival, University of North Carolina, Greensboro, 1963 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Exhibition Installations -- Long Point Gallery, 1977-1983 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Exhibition Installations -- Fine Arts Work Center, Provincetown, 1986 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Exhibition Installations -- Portland Museum of Art, 1987 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Exhibition Installations -- Hunter College, 1987 (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Exhibition Installations -- "Fritz Bultman: A Retrospective," New Orleans Museum of Art, 1993 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Exhibition Installations -- "Fritz Bultman: A Retrospective," Provincetown Art Association and Museum, 1994 (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - Exhibition Installations -- "Herskovic Collection," Provincetown Art Association and Museum, 1994 (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - Exhibition Installations -- Gallery Schlesinger, 1997 (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - People -- Fritz Bultman, circa 1940-circa 1960s; undated (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - People -- Fritz Bultman, Renate Ponsold, photographer, 1976-1984 (Box 10, Folder 21)
  - People -- Fritz and Jean Bultman, 1976-1979 (Box 10, Folder 22)
  - People -- Fritz and Johann Bultman, 1964 (Box 10, Folder 23)
  - People -- Fritz Bultman with Others, 1953-circa 1960s; undated (Box 10, Folder 24)
  - People -- Jeanne Bultman, circa 1940-1957 (Box 10, Folder 25)
  - People -- Johann Bultman, 1964 (Box 10, Folder 26)
  - People -- Family and Friends, 1935-circa 1940s (Box 10, Folder 27)
  - People -- Hans Hofmann, Herbert Matter, photographer, undated (Box 10, Folder 28)
  - People -- Hans Hofmann and Miz Hofmann, 1940-1945 (Box 10, Folder 29)
  - People -- Long Point Gallery Artists, 1977 (Box 10, Folder 30)
  - Places -- Bernhard Crypt, 1977 (Box 10, Folder 31)
  - Places -- Flinders Island, Tasmania, Australia, undated (Box 10, Folder 32)
  - Places -- Grand Union Hotel, undated (Box 10, Folder 33)
  - Places -- Provincetown, MA, Renate Ponsold, photographer, 1982 (Box 10, Folder 34)